<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<poems>

 <poem>
   <title>For Today</title>
   <date>2015/2016</date>
   <text>
     I felt you long ago
     Your arms are mine
     I met you long ago
     Now we're dancing

     Your smile
     Like happiness
     Your eyes
     Like it is everything for you
     that matters

     The dance is over
     You are trying to be good
     The life is harder
     You are trying to be good
   </text>
   <note>
     One day I returned home and there was
     this smell of her parfume on my hands.
     I dared to dream about her just for that day.
   </note>
 </poem>

 <poem>
   <title>Nature Conquers</title>
   <date>August 2017</date>
   <text>
     Alone in the mountains
     Nature conquers everything
     Our minds, our hearts
     Our future and the past

     Suddenly you are sitting
     Looking at the endless lake
     Cottages full of solitude behind you
     Cottages full of nature

     Your feet are pleasantly frozen
     The no emotion sun above you
     You can’t see any path behind or ahead
     You found yourself in a different way

     You have nothing now
     You are nothing now
     So just take a step
     And let the nature conquers you
   </text>
   <note>
     I was sitting inside while outside was rainnig.
     I was in Norway on my holiday. The day before
     I hiked the surrounded mountains. For the whole
     day I met just one person. I was tottaly overcomed
     by nature.
   </note>
 </poem>

 <poem>
   <title>Je zvláštní takto žít</title>
   <date>Říjen 2017</date>
   <text>
     Je zvláštní takto žít
     Ráno vstaneš a jdeš
     A možná, že taky ne
     Nevím

     Věčně přemýšlíš, kdo jsi
     Taky kdo nejsi
     Nebo si lehneš
     A ležíš

     Každopádně je to zvláštní
     Nic nevíš, a přitom se snažíš
     Nějak být a snít
     Věřit
   </text>
   <note>
     Jednoho dne jsem si lehnul a přemýšlel
     jsem o tom, jak je život absurdní. Můžete jít
     po ulici a nějaký blázen vás zastřelí a vy
     skončíte. Není zvláštní takto žít?
   </note>
 </poem>

 <poem>
   <title>Why Are You Still So Far Away?</title>
   <date>March 2018</date>
   <text>
     I guess I could have told you this
     About those dreams in joyful days
     Not so happy as you might think
     Also about the ones in dark
     Not so hopeless as you might feel
     All of this
     When you have asked me
     Why are you still so far away?

     I guess I could have hugged you strong
     With all my great beliefs in you
     That closeness would have done the deed
     I’m sorry just a bit for me
     Sometimes one should at least do something nice
     All of this
     When you have thought
     Why are you still so far away?

     I trust you dear in seeing me
     So what would be the point in giving up on you
     I like it here
     In your struggle and in your happiness
     Your moody face is suddenly changed and even you don’t know why
     I’m all in your playful smile
     Full of kindness, full of kindness
     All of this and slightly more when we are living
     Why are you still so far away?
   </text>
   <note>
     The neverending struggle between introverts
     and extroverts. The feeling of loving someone
     so much but actually have nothing to say to them.
   </note>
 </poem>

 <poem>
   <title>First Glimpse of Autumn</title>
   <date>September 2018</date>
   <text>
     After numerous weeks of devastating heat
     First glimpse of Autumn finally arrives
     It starts with a stormy rain so dense, so you cannot see through it
     And then on the second day the sun almost lazily breaks from its prison
     Suddenly, the cold breeze is no more freezing but comforting
     There is this key change inside your body, inside your soul
     Almost, as some forgotten god is calling you for patience
     Almost, as this is the only life you've ever had
   </text>
   <note>
     The moment when the autumn arrives and
     after heavy rain there is this fresh air.
   </note>
 </poem>

 <poem>
   <title>Life in Reverse</title>
   <date>December 2018</date>
   <text>
     I've been dead so many times that I've lost count
     No, I don’t mean inside but literally dead
     Imagine losing all of your dreams every now and then
     In such moments life simply cease out
     Thank God for always bringing me back
     I guess I call it Phoenix stage

     Come to think of it I have a handful of funeral songs
     And not until today I dear to dream about a wedding one
     You would think I'm not gonna mention the name
     But hey, let’s keep this honest
     It’s Into My Arms by my dear friend Nick
     Because what could be possibly better than kind words of such a man?

     I also have you on my mind
     Simply cause you are everywhere where my joy is
     Am I feeling happiness? I guess I am
     Am I fearless now? For sure not
     But maybe it’s finally a life worth giving
     And when the end will come, I should only see some kind of light
   </text>
   <note>
     I was thinking about how miserable I was in the
     past and how I'm actually getting better and better.
     It almost seems as if I was living life in reverse.
   </note>
 </poem>

 <poem>
   <title>Grasping Healing</title>
   <date>August 2019</date>
   <text>
     Again my soul is dying hard
     Sorry I think myself apart
     The surface silent mourning now
     The inside stormy question how

     I don’t trust in my guts anymore
     The saints have never opened the door
     I'm screaming Jesus the only one
     Forever present under the burning sun

     Equations could convince for a while
     Brother show me your fakeish smile
     I must decide yet everything’s a lie
     O Lord have mercy on me and let me try

     Cause deaf is striking chords on my guitar
     Cause gray is reading poems on my own
     Cause blind is your beauty to my eyes
   </text>
   <note>
     Depression.
   </note>
 </poem>

 <poem>
   <title>Longing</title>
   <date>October 2019</date>
   <text>
     I miss you my darling one
     You were never here but that’s just what I do
     I miss you my dearest one
     You are gone for forever but I…

     My guts are twisting inside out
     By your face I'm tortured in my dreams
     I'm kicking and screaming for your love
     Let’s be honest I'm just dying here alive

     I wish I could touch you lightly like a breeze
     I long to press your body till we collapse
     I dare say: “Kiss me hard”
     I dare say: “Let’s make thousands of children and spend the life together”

     But remember you are there
     You are forever gone
     And I'm here all alone
   </text>
   <note>
     Sometimes being single is easy sometimes not. Sometimes you
     have this energy inside of you and you have no one to give it to.
   </note>
 </poem>
 
 <poem>
   <title>Happens to the Heart</title>
   <date>January 2020</date>
   <text>
     I always hide the truth in me
	 Not that I would be lying to you
	 It's just all things are hard to see
	 It’s just all things are hard to bear
	 The earth is spinning still the same
	 My world is broken deep apart 
	 No-one around to curse or blame
	 What happens to the heart 
	 
	 This living does not worth the fight
	 I’m slowly dying in your eyes
	 There always be another night
	 To touch the stars, to scream my lungs
	 I dreamt about loving you dear
	 But it was just bodies in the dark
	 Don’t know the feeling fighting fear
	 What happens to the heart
	 
	 So now I’m roaming streets of Brno
	 Tonight I drink black beer alone
	 I’m gonna be a builder of Lego
	 To think about nothing at all
	 Everybody has gone crazy for real
	 They cannot give you genuine smile
	 You always hiding, always fake
	 What happens to the heart
	 
	 I’m hypnotized by the window line
	 To take one step and jump straight down
	 Oh, the torture bed for my twisted spine
	 You’re vomiting through the toilet hole
	 You’re beautiful girl with tired face
	 I cannot even reach your soul
	 God, I cannot even hold your tears
	 What happens to the heart
	 
	 And just like that the heart is sank
	 I guess we used to dance in pain
	 We always wanted to win all sides
	 So naturally we lost it all
	 And now the heart is buried down
	 Under it all and it’s taking too long
	 I wonder how long before the damage is done
	 I wonder what happens to the heart
   </text>
   <note>
     The tittle and the structure of the poem is inspired by Leonard Cohen's song Happens to the Heart. 
	 The tittle got me into thinking about how much can take your heart if you are unwell for a long time.
	 Where is the point of not being able to come back, of not being able to restore oneself and to forget.
   </note>
 </poem>
 
 <poem>
   <title>Raped Love</title>
   <date>February 2020</date>
   <text>
     You see, they are so sweet
	 They’re like a candy floss
	 Like a little kitten, they’re too cute
	 No one can dispute
	 Holding hands, whispering huge words 
	 Forever and ever, yeah, forever and ever
	 They are fated, they are so into each other
	 You see, that must be it, the story from fairytales

	 Slow down and take a breath dear
	 Candy floss just decay your teeth
	 Kittens are stupid, troublesome and naive
	 In couple of years, maybe even weeks, you will see
	 It’s obvious they never liked each other
	 They are just too in love
	 In this very moment nothing could be above
	 But the time is always coming for the big love
	 
	 But what about them?
	 You surely see they are something different
	 They are so long together that you cannot say who is who
	 They are always smiling to each other
	 They are living together
	 Going for holidays by their car 
	 One day they were singing crazily to a tune
	 I expect they will marry soon
	 
	 Don’t be childish
	 They are trapped in a cage 
	 So, naturally they have to sing crazily
	 Smile is horrible twist of the mouth 
	 They just got used to each other
	 That’s not living together, that’s rather dying together
	 They got stuck in a ridiculous pose
	 That’s why you cannot tell one from the other
	 
	 And what about these two?
	 They used to be best friends 
	 Now, they are something more
	 When he fell, she was terrified
	 When she cried, he was petrified
	 I’m sure they would give life for each other
	 Proof of love on every corner 
	 Their life is going to be peaceful love
	 
	 You quite right, they were truly best friends
	 And I’m quite sure they still are
	 “Something more” is such a cheap phrase
	 Cause is it truly more? 
	 More often it is less, I would guess
	 Friends help each other and so they helped themselves
	 Cause to be left alone was simply unbearable
	 To face the unknown in such an age was infinite
	 
	 Oh, but I know a guy and a girl, and they are infinite…
	 
	 Oh, yeah, I know them too and they are true
	 There’s nothing much left to say 
	 And that’s how you know that’s it 
	 
	 What is it?
	 
	 I don’t know
	 It used to be called love but nowadays love is raped
	 Love is not what it used to be in the old books
	 Love is hanging on a billboard
	 Love is a cheap package for our joy
	 Love is something untouchable and sacred
	 Love is something mysterious
	 You either feel it or you don’t 
	 You cannot work on it, it’s a miracle!
	 We live under the eye of a new god
	 God of love, the only one
	 
	 Everyone screaming I’m in love!
	 There are so many loves as there are man 
	 It doesn’t matter if you are going to hate each other
	 Or if you are going to get divorced 
	 Or if you are going to scream that your girlfriend was a fucking bitch
	 Or if you are going to betray him in the worst possible way
	 No, nowadays this is just a byproduct
	 
	 What matters is that you are persuaded you have experienced the true love
	 Because no-one can possibly lead life without experiencing the true love
	 So we just settle with our little lies and called them the true love
	 So the god of love, the only one, is satisfied
	 
	 This may seem to you as cynicism
	 But if you think of it, it’s pretty romantic
   </text>
   <note>
     This poem is sort of a conversation between a naive and cynic person. But if you think of it the cynic person 
	 is rather romantic because he/she is persuaded that almost no love is real and that there is something "more" 
	 that not so many people can achieve. 
   </note>
 </poem>
 
 <poem>
   <title>What's For?</title>
   <date>March 2020</date>
   <text>
     And what is the life good for?
     If you’re not able to say what’s right
     If you’re not able to say what’s wrong
     
     The sky is blue and the grass is green
     The dead is near and the Sun is heat
     We love our brothers and so our sisters
     We want to bath our feet in a spring 
     And sing, sing, sing!
     
     I’ve been there too, I've also tried to doubt 
     To doubt simple facts in life 
     But it’s just for fools 
     You think, you are a martyr
     But you are nothing but a joke
     
     But tell me honestly
     Would you care for something that’s permanent for forever?
     And have you ever been doubtless about something that matters?
     It seems that everything that matters to you is relative 
     Doesn’t it? 
     
     Once there was a painter
     His canvas was white
     He started just with one color
     Sparkling with joy
     But as he got older 
     He tried to get it better
     He tried to come up with a new color every now and then
     Oh, how he wished for a painting that would be perfect
     Perfect for everyone
     Yes, everyone could come up with a new color
     Potentially he ended up with gray 
     Color of nothingness
     Color of emptiness
     Now, he is desperate
     For every color he adds the painting is even more gray
     Now he wishes for a fresh start
     He would keep his canvas just for himself
     He would paint just with his favorite
     But gray is never gonna be white again
     
     And what is the life good for?
     If you are able to say what’s right
     If you are able to say what’s wrong
   </text>
   <note>
     The more you get older the harder is to say what actually matters and what doesn't. 
	 Although there are things/ideas/feelings that are hard to doubt unless you don't want 
	 to doubt everything (what's the point of asking yourself if the sky is really blue?),
     almost everything that matters to us can be doubt. The older you get the more opinions 
	 you are going to hear and accept as possible answers. But what happens if you have 
	 too many answers for everything. Suddenly you don't know what is right or wrong. You
	 realize that there is no such thing as right or wrong and you are desperate. You start
	 to ask what is this life even for? Really, what is the meaning to live for? Because if 
	 there is none than why am I even trying?
   </note>
 </poem>

</poems>
