<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<poems>

    <poem>
      <title>Various Ways to Go</title>
      <date>May 2020</date>
      <text>
        One night you may lie down your bones and chest
        You don’t have time to suck eternal rest
        Breakfast, chili peppers and crusty bread
        Your heart is sorry
        But this is the last night
        The last night of your ever-caring heart
        Newborn is crying tears of love for good
        I’m sitting outside reading worn-out book
        I’m taking another log to keep me warm
        Farewell my friend
        Let’s hope that dead by necessity awaits us all

        Guitar is feeling fingers on its neck
        Your songs are passions drowning out your voice
        You let your soul to dwell in vain for years
        And now the strings are broken
        You let them to define your whole life fully
        There is nothing left, there is no point
        I’m dancing with Mary spinning circles and hope
        If my strings are broken down, I try to blow
        If there is a cloud it doesn’t mean the stars were fake all along
        You were good my friend
        Let’s hope that death by error will miss us all

        He is picking success on his own
        The way to stars is easy and crystal clear
        His hands are holding the life with clenched fists
        He often sighs:
        “No one can take it from me,
        No one can take it from me…”
        But the violin does not dissolve in him as it should
        But the kisses do not transcend to her as they should
        The suffering is mild and dishonest
        I pity you my fellow human, dead by soul damage is the worst
        Let’s believe, for souls are almighty
      </text>
      <note>
        Often we are worried about death, but what if we are dead inside already?
        Hopefully there is always a way from this unfortunate state.
      </note>
    </poem>


    <poem>
      <title>Embracing Solitude</title>
      <date>July 2020</date>
      <text>
        Treacherous claws of despair
        What have I done to thee?
        To walking by like a murderer
        In a foreign country
        Where no one knows my crimes

        I wonder what led them astray
        What have I done to them?
        To judge me so bluntly
        “It’s clear! You killed the bird!”
        But what if I saved it?

        No, that was not what I meant
        But everyone’s turning faces
        It would be wrong to fight
        To fight for something that’s obviously right
        Curse me! I must be a hideous being…

        Though no man is an island
        Before God I’m alone
        Before eternal inner self
        Yes, here I am trembling with fear
        So anxious about this endless loneliness
        That I cannot be saved from
        That I don’t want to be saved from
        Yes, here I am embracing solitude
        Embracing my beautiful deformity
      </text>
      <note>
        I had a dream and in this dream everyone was leaving me because of who I was.
        Although it was dreadful for the most part, at the end there was a strange feeling of serenity.
      </note>
    </poem>


    <poem>
      <title>You Know Nothing</title>
      <date>August 2020</date>
      <text>
        Sit down and watch the lake go misty mild
        Forget what is known about your hellish star
        Remember to always have a heaven reason why
        And please don’t ever, don’t ever, don’t go wild

        Old oak is wrapping childish dreams to roots
        Your hair is intertwined with branches high
        You felt him back then, now you know the rules
        You should not sell the heart in search for the truth

        I’m holding saltcellar and a loaf of bread
        I’m sitting straight and hopefully true to you
        I felt it back then, now I… (know nothing?)
        I should not sell the heart for a feeble cry

        A little bit of magic is stuffed in all
        A little bit of eternity in all
        A little bit that is never to be known
        A little bit that is always to be shown

        Sit down and watch the lake go misty mild
        Forget what is known about your hellish star
        Remember to always have a heaven reason why
        And please don’t ever, don’t ever, don’t go wild
      </text>
      <note>
        There is something in everything. Something untouchable.
        There is no tree nor any river in the real world. Or in other words you will never know neither of them.
        You know nothing.
      </note>
    </poem>


    <poem>
      <title>Sooner or Later</title>
      <date>September 2020</date>
      <text>
        Was I cold inside the night you offered me a coat?
        Did you feel some inner voice that was dying young?
        Though hearts cannot be touched without a reason
        What was it?
        Did we breathe?
        Just a dream or something
        Something to die for

        But sooner or later, apple of my eye
        Our souls will slowly bind us close
        And there will be no collision
        In the whole wide universe
        Just a peaceful realization of some deeper traces
        That will guide us to better places
        Where the past will become a strange illusion
        And we will return to fairytales once again
        For the last time and never more
      </text>
      <note>
        Maybe the most important events in life are the most natural ones.
        Maybe you will not scream, but you will be silent. Maybe you will not cry,
        but you will have a little smile on your lips. Maybe nothing will colide,
        but everything will fit. 
      </note>
    </poem>


</poems>
